{
    "id": "57a1b7b7bb71438e8a6f668c0660fc74",
    "title": "Gap Filling Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "There was ………………………… anything in the box.",
            "description": "Hardly means scarcely. ",
            "answers": [
                "hard",
                "hardly"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3f1cb36aa1124c609fe4c41e28620871"
        },
        {
            "question": "There lay ……………………………… books on the table.",
            "description": "A few indicates a small number few means almost none.",
            "answers": [
                "few",
                "a few",
                "a little"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "534c6527eec846488577065654342ac5"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………………. the thunderstorm approaching, we rushed indoors.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "See",
                "Seen",
                "Seeing"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "10c22058b4bc4b2093ff55e0fb9726f7"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………………. on tip-toe, he reached for the apple.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Standing",
                "Stand",
                "Stood"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1ee2a56063a545e894154cc3c292bdb1"
        },
        {
            "question": "Would you mind ……………………………. the door?",
            "description": "An ing form is used after would you mind. ",
            "answers": [
                "to close",
                "closing",
                "close"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7217b1a9cb2642fab268320a0c11125c"
        },
        {
            "question": "You ……………………………… attend the meeting.",
            "description": "The modal auxiliary need is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "needn't",
                "needn't to",
                "don't need"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "62d9473b99724ec2b12142705a450cce"
        },
        {
            "question": "You had better ………………………….. a doctor.",
            "description": "The bare infinitive is used after had better. ",
            "answers": [
                "consult",
                "consulting",
                "to consult"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d6c64bd99816476f92501866f12e56d4"
        },
        {
            "question": "You don’t need …………………………….. all questions.",
            "description": "When need is an ordinary verb, it is followed by a to-infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "answer",
                "to answer",
                "answering"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "249f4c29f2ce49c18a71fb6e5e2035a5"
        },
        {
            "question": "Beethoven is ……………………………… than most other composers.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "great",
                "greater",
                "greatest"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7bd25e089e4845a99c99cfd630617112"
        },
        {
            "question": "I prefer watching TV …………………………… reading books.",
            "description": "Prefer is followed by the preposition to. ",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "over",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c7c2e09033d24aef83dd22f5e4dba2f2"
        },
        {
            "question": "He is ………………………………. of my four children.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "the young",
                "the younger",
                "the youngest"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "b72d01c3b78442229cdf3aa9aa0052ef"
        },
        {
            "question": "The older we grow, ………………………………. we become.",
            "description": "The + comparative is used in both clauses in this structure. ",
            "answers": [
                "the wise",
                "wiser",
                "the wiser",
                "the wisest"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "74ec16083e4a466c84c37112f90b5ab7"
        }
    ]
}